# **Evan Lu**

evalu802@gmail.com | (510) 603-8737 | Alameda & Merced, CA | waffles-codes.github.io

### **SUMMARY**

As a second-year Computer Science and Engineering student at UC Merced, I have hands-on experience coding robots for The Aztechs. I excel in learning on the fly, problem solving, and adapting to new challenges. My strong communication skills and creativity are complemented by my attention to detail and self-motivation, driving me to continuously learn and innovate.

### **EDUCATION**

### Lanev College, Oakland, CA -

Associate of Science - Computer Programming

**SEPTEMBER 2019 - JUNE 2023** 

- Cumulative GPA: 3.95/4.0
- Relevant Education Experience: Object Oriented Programming in C++, Data Structures & Algorithms (Java), Microcomputer Assembly Language (x86 ASM & C++), Calculus I-III, Statistics

### University of California, Merced, Merced, CA-

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science & Engineering

**AUGUST 2023- CURRENT** 

- Cumulative GPA: 3.9/4.0
- Relevant Education Experience: Algorithm Design and Analysis (C++), Probability and Statistics (Python), Discrete Mathematics, Linear Algebra, Physics

### **EXPERIENCE**

### The Aztechs, Alameda, CA

Lead Programmer

SEPTEMBER 2021 - MAY 2023

- Programmed robots in Java (2021-22) and Kotlin (2022-23)
- Developed new methods using computer vision, gyros, and encoders for automatic robot aiming, balancing, and positioning
- Enhanced existing codebases from previous team members
- Collaborated with mechanical and electrical teams
- Mentored a junior team member in programming and Git usage

### **PROJECTS**

### **Robot Hand**

- Created a rock-paper-scissors robot using a Raspberry Pi, code on GitHub
- Integrated MediaPipe, machine learning, and OpenCV in Python, employing multi-core parallelization and low-level motor control
- Completed as a high school passion project, demonstrating advanced technical skills and problem-solving

## **Timelapse App**

- Identified limitations in OBS for creating screen timelapses efficiently
- Developed custom recording software using Python
- Learned a lot about GUI design in python, the MSS library, and juggling image data in RAM

#### waffles-codes.github.io

- Gained foundational knowledge of website structure with HTML and enhanced styling skills using CSS for visually appealing designs.
- Polished problem-solving skills by troubleshooting layout and styling issues, learning to effectively debug and refine website code.
- Learned to create responsive designs to fit both desktop and mobile webpages.

### **SKILLS & AWARDS**

- Skills: Always Learning, Attention to Detail, Critical Thinking, Communication, Collaboration, Adaptability, Analysis, Problem Solving, Technical, Self Motivation, Creativity, Public Speaking
- Programming: C++, Java, Kotlin, Python, x86 ASM, HTML, Linux CMD line, Javascript, Git
- Interests: Robotics, Graphic Design, Video Creation, Arts & Crafts, Language Learning (programming or otherwise), Multiplayer Games
- Awards:
  - o Chancellor's Honor List & Dean's Honor List UC Merced
  - o Academic Honor Student Peralta Community College District
  - Outstanding Student & Lifelong Learner Alameda Science and Technology Institute